<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="./_c74_ref.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>

<!--This file has been automatically generated by Doctor Max. DO NOT EDIT THIS FILE DIRECTLY.-->

<c74object name="sy.find" module="sy">

	<digest>
		Find occurrences of substrings in a symbol
	</digest>

	<description>
		Searches all the occurrences of substrings in a given symbol.
	</description>

	<!--METADATA-->
	<metadatalist>
		<metadata name="author">Daniele Ghisi</metadata>
		<metadata name="tag">sy</metadata>
	</metadatalist>

	<!--INLETS-->
	<inletlist>
		<inlet id="0" type="INLET_TYPE">
			<digest>
				Element or elements to be searched
			</digest>
			<description>
			</description>
		</inlet>
		<inlet id="1" type="INLET_TYPE">
			<digest>
				Pattern to be found
			</digest>
			<description>
			</description>
		</inlet>
	</inletlist>

	<!--OUTLETS-->
	<outletlist>
		<outlet id="0" type="INLET_TYPE">
			<digest>
				Indices of occurrences
			</digest>
			<description>
				The index of an occurrence is the index of the character (meant as code point) where the pattern starts, counting from 1.
			</description>
		</outlet>
		<outlet id="1" type="INLET_TYPE">
			<digest>
				Indices of atoms where occurrences are found
			</digest>
			<description>
			</description>
		</outlet>
	</outletlist>

	<!--ARGUMENTS-->
	<objarglist>
		<objarg name="pattern" optional="1" type="symbol">
			<digest>
				Pattern to be found
			</digest>
			<description>
				The optional argument sets the initial value for the pattern to be found.
			</description>
		</objarg>
	</objarglist>

	<!--MESSAGES-->
	<methodlist>
		<method name="bang">
			<arglist />
			<digest>
				Change find
			</digest>
			<description>
				Changes the find of the most recently received input list.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="list">
			<arglist />
			<digest>
				Find pattern
			</digest>
			<description>
				A <m>list</m> in the left inlet triggers the search of the pattern set via the right inlet in any of the elements
				of such list. The matches are output from the first outlet, along with their indices (starting Unicode code point position of each match, counting from 1),
				and the indices of the symbols in the list where they have been found (counting from 1).
				Numeric atoms of the list are automatically converted to symbols.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="symbol">
			<arglist />
			<digest>
				Set pattern
			</digest>
			<description>
			</description>
		</method>
	</methodlist>

	<!--ATTRIBUTES-->
	<attributelist>
		<attribute name="alternate" get="1" set="1" type="int" size="1">
			<digest>
				Ignore Alternate Characters
			</digest>
			<description>
				Toggles the ability to move the differences of punctuation and alternate characters from the first to the fourth strength
				level (see <m>strength</m> attribute). When this attribute is active, for instance, it means that up to the tertiary level symbols like
				"ab" and "a-b" are equal. Defaults to 0.
			</description>
			<attributelist>
				<attribute name="label" get="1" set="1" type="symbol" size="1" value="Ignore Alternate Characters" />
				<attribute name="style" get="1" set="1" type="symbol" size="1" value="onoff" />
			</attributelist>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name="maxdecimals" get="1" set="1" type="int" size="1">
			<digest>
				Maximum Decimal Digits For Number Conversion
			</digest>
			<description>
				Sets the maximum number of decimals to be used for the conversion from number
				to symbol, in case the <m>numbers</m> attribute is set to "Convert To Symbol".
			</description>
			<attributelist>
				<attribute name="category" get="1" set="1" type="symbol" size="1" value="Behavior" />
				<attribute name="label" get="1" set="1" type="symbol" size="1" value="Maximum Decimal Digits For Number Conversion" />
				<attribute name="style" get="1" set="1" type="symbol" size="1" value="text" />
			</attributelist>
		</attribute>
		<attribute name="strength" get="1" set="1" type="int" size="1">
			<digest>
				Comparison Strength
			</digest>
			<description>
				Sets the comparison strength for the substring matching.
				The strength of the comparison can be set to different levels. <br /> <br />
				- <b>Primary Level</b>: this denotes differences between base characters (for example, "a" &gt; "b").
				It is the strongest difference. For example, dictionaries are divided into different sections by base character. <br /> <br />
				- <b>Secondary Level</b>: accents in the characters are considered secondary differences (for example, "as" &gt; "às" &gt; "at").
				Other differences between letters can also be considered secondary differences, depending on the language.
				A secondary difference is ignored when there is a primary difference anywhere in the strings.
				Note: In some languages (such as Danish), certain accented letters are considered to be separate base characters.
				In most languages, however, an accented letter only has a secondary difference from the unaccented version of that letter <br /> <br />
				- <b>Tertiary Level</b> (default): Upper and lower case differences in characters are distinguished at the tertiary level
				(for example, "ao" &gt; "Ao" &gt; "aò"). In addition, a variant of a letter differs from the base form on the tertiary level.
				Another example is the difference between large and small Kana. A tertiary difference is ignored when
				there is a primary or secondary difference anywhere in the strings. <br /> <br />
				- <b>Quaternary Level</b>: when punctuation is ignored at level 1-3 (i.e. the <m>alternate</m> attribtue is set),
				an additional level can be used to distinguish words
				with and without punctuation (for example, "ab" &gt; "a-b" &gt; "aB"). This difference is ignored when there is a primary, secondary or
				tertiary difference. The quaternary level should only be used if ignoring punctuation is required (i.e. the <m>alternate</m> attribtue is set)
				or when processing Japanese text. <br /> <br />
				- <b>Identical Level</b>: when all other levels are equal, the identical level is used as a tiebreaker.
				The Unicode code point values of the NFD form of each string are compared at this level, just in case there is no difference at levels 1-4.
				For example, Hebrew cantillation marks are only distinguished at this level.
				This level should be used sparingly, as only code point values differences between two strings is an extremely rare occurrence.
				Using this level substantially decreases the performance for
				both incremental comparison and sort key generation (as well as increasing the sort key length). <br /> <br />
				This distinction is completely inherited by the ICU collation standards: see http://userguide.icu-project.org/collation/concepts.
			</description>
			<attributelist>
				<attribute name="label" get="1" set="1" type="symbol" size="1" value="Comparison Strength" />
				<attribute name="style" get="1" set="1" type="symbol" size="1" value="enumindex" />
			</attributelist>
		</attribute>
	</attributelist>

	<!--SEEALSO-->
	<seealsolist>
		<seealso name="sy.replace" />
		<seealso name="regexp" />
	</seealsolist>

	<misc name = "Input">
		<entry name ="Inlet 1 (symbol/list)">
			<description>
				Element or elements to be searched.
			</description>
		</entry>
		<entry name ="Inlet 2 (symbol)">
			<description>
				Pattern to be found.
			</description>
		</entry>
	</misc>

	<misc name = "Output">
		<entry name ="Outlet 1 (list)">
			<description>
				Indices of occurrences.
				The index of an occurrence is the index of the character (meant as code point) where the pattern starts, counting from 1.
			</description>
		</entry>
		<entry name ="Outlet 2 (list)">
			<description>
				Indices of atoms where occurrences are found.
			</description>
		</entry>
	</misc>

</c74object>